Finding Aid for the Donald A. Glaser Papers, 1943-2013, bulk 1949-2003 GlaserDA
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Series 8 Audio Visual, ca. 1949-2006; 8
  - Subseries 2 35mm slides, ca. 1951-1988
    - Sperling, G., Movement perception in computer-driven visual displays, Behavior Research Methods & Instrumentation Vol. 8, No. 2 1976 - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_04C_06; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 6)
    - Land, E.H., The Retinex theory and color vision, Scientific American Vol. 237, No. 6 1977 - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_04C_07; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 7)
    - Brain figures - Scientific American 1979, GlaserDA_08_02_04C_08; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 8)
    - Ullman, S. (1979) The interpretation of visual motion. Oxford, England: MIT Press - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_04C_09; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 9)
    - Frisby, J.P. - Figures, ca. 1980-1985; GlaserDA_08_02_04C_10; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 10)
    - Kandel, E.R. - Figures, ca. 1981; GlaserDA_08_02_04C_11; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 11)
    - Grimson, W.E.L. - Figures, ca. 1981-1983; GlaserDA_08_02_04C_12; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 12)
    - Regan, D. - Channels figures, 1982; GlaserDA_08_02_04C_13; 35mm (Box C-8.4, Folder 13)
    - Marr, D. (1982) Vision: A computational investigation into the human representation and processing of visual information. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_05C_01; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 1)
    - Van Essen, D.C. - Figures, ca. 1982; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_02; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 2)
    - Cortical anatomy, ca. 1982-1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_03; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 3)
    - Neuroscience lecture slides, ca. 1982-1988; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_04; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 4)
    - Brain blood flow figures - Scientific American, ca. 1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_05; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 5)
    - Caelli, T. - Figures, ca. 1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_06; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 6)
    - Mach Bands, ca. 1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_07; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 7)
    - NMR imaging, ca. 1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_08; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 8)
    - Superconducting quantum interference devices (SQUIDs), ca. 1983; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_09; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous neuroscience slides, ca. 1983-1988; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_10; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 10)
    - Feynman, R. - Figures, ca. 1984; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_11; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 11)
    - Van Santen J.P.H., Sperling G., Temporal covariance model of human motion perception, Vol. 1, No. 5 1984; Elaborated reichardt detectors, Vol. 2, No. 2 1985. Journal of the Optical Society of America - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_05C_12; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 12)
    - Wolfram, S. & Packard, N. - Cellular automata, ca. 1984-1985; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_13; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 13)
    - Illusions, ca. 1984-1986; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_14; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 14)
    - Kelly, D.H., Visual processing of moving stimuli, Journal of the Optical Society of America A Vol. 2, No. 2 1985 - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_05C_15; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 15)
    - Watson, A.B. & Ahumada, A.J., Model of human visual-motion sensing, Journal of the Optical Society of America, Vol. 2, No. 2 1985 - Figures, GlaserDA_08_02_05C_16; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 16)
    - Random dot stereograms, 1985; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_17; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 17)
    - Bowne, S.F. - Motion figures, 1985; 1988; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_18; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 18)
    - Color, ca. 1985-1986; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_19; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 19)
    - Acoustic illusions, ca. 1986; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_20; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 20)
    - Chaudhuri, Avijit - Figures, ca. 1987; GlaserDA_08_02_05C_21; 35mm (Box C-8.5, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 3 Photographic negatives, 1963
    - Molecular biology - Roll I, 1963 May 16; GlaserDA_08_03_06C_01; Negatives with prints (Box C-8.6, Folder 1)
      Negatives developed for 4 minutes at 75° F using Microdol-X
    - Molecular biology - Roll III, 1963 May 16; GlaserDA_08_03_06C_02; Negatives with prints (Box C-8.6, Folder 2)
      Negatives developed for 7 minutes at 75° F using Microdol-X. Image 1/2 scale
    - Molecular biology - F1, F2, F3, undated; GlaserDA_08_03_06C_03; Negatives with prints (Box C-8.6, Folder 3)
    - Molecular biology - Series C, undated; GlaserDA_08_03_06C_04; Negatives (Box C-8.6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4 Audio, ca. 1966-2003
    - How do Bacteria Work?, 1966 March 10; Audio reel (Box C-8.6, Folder 5)
    - Donner Lecture, 1975 November 6; Audio reel (Box C-8.6, Folder 6)
    - Tromba Marina: John Introduces His Piece, 2003; GlaserDA_08_04_06C_07 (Box C-8.6, Folder 7)
      Compact disc. 9 min. 26 sec.
    - Tromba Marina: Thow Quartet, 2003; GlaserDA_08_04_06C_08 (Box C-8.6, Folder 8)
      Compact disc. 10 min. 26 sec.
    - Untitled audio reel, undated; Audio reel (Box C-8.6, Folder 9)
    - Hologram Theory: Bohm, Hidley, Pribram, undated; DAG_8_6_10_0001; Audio cassette (Box C-8.6, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 5 Film and video, ca. 1960s-2006
    - Untitled film, undated; Super 16 mm (Box C-8.6, Folder 11)
    - Automation Techniques for Identification of Bacterial Colonies, undated; 16 mm. Color. Silent. 14 min. (Box C-8.6, Folder 12)
    - Die Stillen Stars, ca. 1986; VHS. Color. 30 min. (Box C-8.6, Folder 13)
    - Science Board Lectures, Don Glaser: Human Visual Perception, 2002 October 4; VHS. 82 min. (Box C-8.6, Folder 14)
    - University of California Berkeley Physics Colloquium: What can we see, how do we see it, why do we see things that aren't there?, 2004 October 11; GlaserDA_08_05_06C_15; DVD. Color. 73 min. 38 sec. (Box C-8.6, Folder 15)
    - Redwood Center for Theoretical Neuroscience Seminar: Dario Ringach, "Population dynamics in primary visual cortex", 2006 February 28; GlaserDA_08_05_06C_16; DVD. Color. 68 min. 55 sec. (Box C-8.6, Folder 16)